Olive Rush
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Printed Materials, 1879-1967, undated, Series 6:; (Boxes 4-5, 7, OV 13; 1.6 linear feet)
  - Pamphlets, 1896-1962, undated, (2 folders; partially scanned) (Box 5, Folder 36-37)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1908-1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Oversized Clippings, Images, (See Box 5, F19) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Oversized Clippings, Native American Subjects, (See Box 5, F20) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Oversized Reproductions of Rush Artwork, (See Box 5, F23) (Box 7 (sol))
  - Oversized Poster for Plastic Club Exhibition, (See Box 5, F22) (Box 13 (OV))
  - Oversized Reproductions of Rush Artwork, (See Box 5, F23) (Box 13 (OV))
- Photographs, circa 1890-1966, Series 7:; (Boxes 6-7; 0.4 linear feet)
  Photographs in this series depict Olive Rush, her schools, classmates, friends, colleagues, homes, and artwork. Class pictures include a group photograph from the Corcoran School of Art circa 1890, and from the John Herron Art Institute from 1920. Photographs from Rush's Delaware years depict the residents of "Tusculum," a boarding house used by female artists who attended Howard Pyle's studio lectures and criticisms, and the interior of the Howard Pyle studio, where Rush lived with Ethel Pennewill Brown (later Leach) during Pyle's absence in 1911.
  The bulk of photographs of artwork depict Rush's murals in the Midwest and Southwest, some in private residences and businesses, and others created for the Federal Art Project in public facilities. A series of photographs also depict Rush working with local Navajo, Taos, and Apache artists on frescoes at Maisel's Indian Trading Post in Albuquerque
  Dates given in parentheses are execution dates of artwork and should not be confused with record dates. Apart from installation views, murals, and frescoes, photographs of artwork have not been digitized.
  - Portrait of Olive Rush, undated, (2 folders, including copy) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Olive Rush with Paintings, circa 1940-1960 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Olive Rush Studio and Garden, Santa Fe, 1966, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Class Pictures, Corcoran School of Art and John Herron Art Institute, circa 1890-1892, 1920, (2 folders, including copy) (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Delaware, "Tusculum," Howard Pyle Studio, circa 1904-1912, (3 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
    (Olive Rush, Ethel Pennewill Brown, Blanche C. Grant, Harriet Roosevelt Richards, and others unidentified)
  - Miscellaneous Early Life, circa 1900-1910 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous People, 1904-1946, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    (Beulah Stevenson and Ethel Pennewill Leach, others unidentified)
  - Miscellaneous Southwestern Scenes, circa 1920-1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Landscapes and Seascapes, 1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Rush and Native American Artists Painting Frescoes at Maisel's Indian Trading Post, Albuquerque, NM; 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    (Rush, Harrison Begay, Awa-Tsireh, Pop Chalee; artwork of Pablita Valerde, Ha-So-De (Narciso Abeyta) and Wilson Dewey shown)
  - Photographs of Artwork (Box 6)
    - Installation Views, Wall Panels in Private Home; undated, (2 folders, including copy) (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
    - Altar Painting, St. Andrew's Episcopal Church, Wilmington, DE (1907), undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Panels, Nathaniel Hawthorne School, Indianapolis, IN (1919), undated, (See also Box 7) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Frescoes, La Fonda Hotel, Santa Fe, NM (1929), undated, (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Mural, Santa Fe Public Library (1934), undated, (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
    - Frescoes in Home of Florence Bartlett, 1934, (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
    - Mural, Biology Building of New Mexico Agricultural College (1935), undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Mural "Osages," Pawhuska, Oklahoma Post Office (1938), undated, (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 26-27)
    - Mural "Antelopes," Florence, Colorado Post Office (1939), undated, (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 28-29)
    - Murals and Frescoes in Private Homes, 1934-1951, undated, (2 folders, including copies) (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
    - Portraits, undated, (2 folders, including copies; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
    - Oils, undated, (2 folders, including copies; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 34-35)
    - Watercolors, undated, (2 folders, including copies; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 36-37)
    - Miscellaneous Artwork, undated, (See also Box 7; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Artwork by Others, 1925, undated, (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Photographic Postcards, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Oversized Photographs of Artwork, (See Box 6, F18 and F38) (Box 7 (sol))